{"posts":[{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Dear Tutors, Could you please entered all of the lab marks that you might have in files, spreadsheets, etc. but not yet copied to SMS yet. Also, please check that you gave marks to both members of each lab pair. Please ensure not to have any \"?\" mark for a submission made without an actually mark. This task need to be completed before this Friday!! Regards, Wael ","answers":[" Hi Wael, mine are mostly done but I have a small number of \"?\" labs I'll have to scrape out of the tar files and finish marking tomorrow. Thanks! "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" On here: https://cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/~cs1521/18s2/tutes/week01/index.php The diagram in the answer for Q4 is incorrect; A should be 6 7 8 after /*B*/. This is correct in the tutors' version but incorrect in the public version. ","answers":[]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi, I'm unwell, is anyone able to take my tute-lab tomorrow afternoon at 1-4? It's in Colombo LG01 and Sitar. Cheers, Ellen ","answers":[" I can do it ",[" Awesome, Thanks Aydin! what's your zid? ",[" no problem. It’s z3437918. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Is it possible to view the practice prac exam questions and students' submissions so I can go through them with those who didn't manage to finish or had bugs? ","answers":[" I've put the questions and exam.tar files under Sample Exams. Because of the way the VLab exam environment is set up, I don't (yet) have access to the submissions. Once I get access, I'll put the submissions under the ~/18s2.work/ppex directory in the class account. "," The starter files are under ~cs1521/ppex/ You'll need to find what one was given to your class, and the spec isn't given only the files. Looks like students work will be in the normal place, but isn't there yet: ~cs1521/18s2.work/ppex/ ",[" Hey Jas, the files.tar aren’t accessible (well 404 not found) on the cgi website. Only the spec is "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" I had a student who wanted to use vim, but found that they couldn’t backspace in insert mode. They had to use ‘x’ outside of insert mode to backspace. Is it possible to set vimrc up with some basic settings like line numbers &amp; syntax highlighting &amp; ability to backspace? And also release the .vimrc file so that students can practise? ","answers":[" The .vimrc file is copied into their account at the start of the exam. They can always modify it if it's causing a problem. One of the tutors told me earlier in the week that the original version of .vimrc was causing problems, so I installed a much simpler one. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Should I tell my students to give weeks late if they forgot to submit their labs, but I’ve seen them demonstrate on time, or should they not submit at all? How does marking work in that case? ","answers":[" I agree that they should submit. Just give them whatever grade you determined after the demo. "," Hello Michael, Absolutely, every mark in the system should be associated with a submission. They have to submit. Regarding they demonstrate on time and forget to submit, my personal opinion, they should of get a penalty for late submission, because they do not have a reason to forget. However, I will leave it up to Jas in this case. Thanks "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" One of my students has special exam provisions. Are there special provisions for the practice exam? ","answers":[" It's impossible to do special provisions *within* your lab class, since the labs tend to be fully booked, and you'll get kicked out after 2 hours. I've been contacting the DSU people individually and am trying to arrange an alternative session where we can book a lab for 3 hours to at least handle all the extra time provisions. ",[" Hey Jas, Is the 3 hour practice exam session going to run? I was just contacted by one of the students in my class this morning, they are meant to have an extra 30 mins per hour of exam. "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Dear Tutors, We are almost by the end of the semester, good work everyone. Just wonder about some tutors who did NOT enter marks into SMS and some others, did not enter marks up to lab 05. Please ensure to do so ASAP Thank you Wael ","answers":[" Hi Wael, I believe that marking is still broken. ",[" cgi/~cs1521/18s2/tutors/sms.py works for me. ",[" Thanks Jashank "],[" Thanks for the link, I didn't even know that that page existed. I was referring to the webCMS marking. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Would someone be able to swap/cover for my tutelab this Tuesday 5-8 at blockhouse G15? ","answers":[" Still available! "," Bump "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" For the week 10 lab, the function signature of inet_ntoa should be char *inet_ntoa(struct in_addr ip) It takes struct in_addr directly, not a pointer. ","answers":[" It also has that the return is dynamically allocated, but it's actually a static buffer. You will segfault if you try in place modifying or freeing. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi, what's the best way to enter marks at the moment? I get a permission error for classrun -rsms, is there another way to do it while webcms marking isn't working? Thanks :) ","answers":[" try classrun -mark. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" I can’t seem to access the week 10 Tutorial. Has it been released yet ","answers":[" It's there now. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hey all, is anyone free to cover for lab assistant on Week 10 Friday, 5th October at 2-4pm? ","answers":[" Hi Kris, i can cover for you. ",[" Awesome, thanks! I'll fill in the form. It's in Sitar (F13B) "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" This part of the assignment spec seems to have a typo: an executable for the command (first token) actually exists stdin is redirected, but without giveng a filename to read from stdin is redirected, but with a filename that is nonexistent or not readable stdin is redirected, but without giving a filename to write to stdin is redirected, but with a filename that is not writeable using !SeqNo but with an invalid sequence number shouldn’t the last two redirection statements be for stdout? Also, it is a bit confusing with the double negative (“If the command line fails any of the above, it should not be placed in the history.” ... fails or doesn’t fail?) ","answers":[" Thanks ... fixed "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi! Is anyone able to swap or cover a tute-lab with me for my 9am-12pm class wed17-brass on the 19th of September ? Would be hugely appreciated!! ","answers":[" Anyone able to take this? Thanks "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Carey is right. I can't bash. ","answers":[" [deleted] ",[" The problem you have is that unset actually unexports your PATH: carey@ubuntu-debug in /tmp/tmp.tAYWld2Pau &gt; echo -e 'OLDPATH=$PATH\\nunset PATH\\nPATH=$OLDPATH\\n' &gt;&gt; test carey@ubuntu-debug in /tmp/tmp.tAYWld2Pau &gt; source ./test carey@ubuntu-debug in /tmp/tmp.tAYWld2Pau &gt; python -c 'import os; print sorted(os.environ.keys())' ['BOLD', 'DBUS_SESSION_BUS_ADDRESS', 'GREEN', 'HOME', 'LANG', 'LANGUAGE', 'LOGNAME', 'LS_COLORS', 'MAGENTA', 'MAIL', 'OLDPWD', 'ORANGE', 'PROMPT_COMMAND', 'PS1', 'PS2', 'PURPLE', 'PWD', 'RESET', 'SHELL', 'SHLVL', 'SSH_CLIENT', 'SSH_CONNECTION', 'SSH_TTY', 'TERM', 'USER', 'XDG_DATA_DIRS', 'XDG_RUNTIME_DIR', 'XDG_SESSION_ID', '_'] "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hey, Is anyone able to swap/cover a tut-lab on Wednesday 19th of September 1-4pm with me? I would really appreciate it. ","answers":[" Can anyone take the class? You'd be a life saver I really can't make it to uni that day. ",[" Hi Oliver, I can cover for you. ",[" Thanks Dylan you're amazing. The class is 1pm-4pm on the 19/09. Tutorial in quad G054 and lab in Sitar. Whats your zid? ",[" 5115658 "]]]," Can you swap for 9-12pm same day? ",[" Unfortunately Ican't :( "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hey, is anyone able to sub a 10-12 lab tomorrow morning in flute? Would be hugely appreciated as I have had something come up early in the morning thanks!! ","answers":[" Lab assistant? I can take care of that, my zID is 5098972 for the form :) ",[" Please let me know whether or not you need me to cover. ",[" Yes that would be perfect! Thanks so much ",[" No problem, let me know once you've sent in the form :) "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" So...Xmark segfaults on me. Any ideas why? $ 1521 classrun -mark Assignments: assign1 lab01 lab02 lab03 lab04 lab05 lab06 lab07 lab08 lab09 lab10 Running Tcl8.5/Tk8.5... Running Xmark3.0... For more info: http://www.cse.unsw.edu.au/~give Segmentation fault ","answers":[" It appears some file in my $HOME is causing this. Trying to figure out what. It's my fonts.conf. The existence of that file (~/.config/fontconfig/fonts.conf) causes the segfault? ",[" Strictly, ~/.config/fontconfig/ that isn't readable across the setuid boundary. I had this bug for a long time, and asked Mei Cheng for help. "]," Nope. What platform? What X windows? What OS? I'll ask Meicheng once I know the above ",[" Happens everywhere I try - SSH forwarding from Linux, VLAB, lab computer. GNOME on my laptop, Xfce on VLAB / lab machine. "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Will students have MIPS syntax highlighting for GUI editors (gedit) in the exam? I've emailed my students on how to set up highlighting on their user .local, but in the exam they won't be able to do this. vim has MIPS syntax highlighting already set up, which gives them an advantage. Also, how does late marking work with labs, if they don't give on time? ","answers":[" I'll try and arrange for my syntax highlighting hack to be set up in the exam environment. I wouldn't be recommending students change text editors, especially for an exam, purely on the basis of syntax highlighting. ",[" There is a syntax available here https://ecs-network.serv.pacific.edu/past-courses/... "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" For MIPS jumps and branches, will students get marked down for omitting nop (in the assignment)? I tend to avoid using nop in SPIM, but I've noticed lots of students are using nop in their code. ","answers":[" jas answered that over on the assignment forum. short answer: as long as students know why it's necessary and have explained as much in their code, it's fine. "," Delayed branches aren't enabled (by default) in SPIM, so there's not much reason to require students to fill a non-existent delay slot with a nop. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi! Is anyone able to take my tutorial next week 11am on wed 5th September? I have a midterm in the morning but should be able to make it for the lab. ","answers":[" I can do it! ",[" Awesome thanks Simon! Can I have your student number for the form? ",[" z5080334 ",[" Ta, that's submitted :) "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hello! I'm unable to take the mon11-flute tut-lab in its entirety this coming Monday; I may make it back in time to take some of the lab, but that's dubious. Any takers? ","answers":[" By coming Monday do you mean tomorrow, 27th August? If so, I can take it. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi, Is anyone able to cover my Wed (22nd) 1-2pm tut? I can still take the lab afterwards. Cheers ","answers":[" happy to do it ",[" Whats your zid anna? ",[" z5114663 "]],[" The tut is in quad G054 "],[" Thanks Anna I really appreciate it :) "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Is anyone able to cover my Thu 3-6 tutlab next week (23rd)? Please let me know, thanks :) ","answers":[" plz :( ",[" Hey, I can do the tute part if no one's able to cover. I probably need to head home at 4 tho. ",[" Thanks for the reply Ellen! Don't worry, Minjie will cover the class for me. ",[" Awesome :) "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi all, I can't make my tutorial/lab this coming week on Wednesday 1-4pm, so I was wondering if anyone would be able to cover me for the tutorial and lab? Sorry if this is the wrong place to ask. ","answers":[" Is anyone else available to cover it please? I'm not sure if people will be notified of this post, I'll make a fresh one early tomorrow in case nobody has responded. "," id be happy to take it ",[" That'd be great thanks, I'll fill out the Mei Cheng's form on the day. ",[" Won't be able to take it anymore, just got an interview slotted for 1 unfortunately, can someone else take it? "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Could someone take my 10am consult today? Sorry it's very last minute. ","answers":[" Did you find someone to fill in? What time does it end? I can take it till 12,but will be a little late. ",[" its 10-12 ",[" Ok Ill cover you. What room is it in? ",[" flite - oboe ",[" Awesome :) ",[" What is your zid? ",[" z5157383 Let me know if you need anymore info "]]]]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Hi, Is marking for labs set up yet? I can't seem to input the marks. ","answers":[" Could you please try now!! ",[" Yes its there now! Thanks Wael "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Dear Tutors, I hope you all having a very good weekend, I wish if you can use the tutor forum for lab substitution so, I can keep track if a lab has been covered or not. Thanks in advanced. ","answers":[]},{"tags":[{"name":"Forums"},{"name":"COMP1521 Tutor Group"}],"question":" Dear Tutors, This is Wael Alghamdi, the course Admin. Welcome and welcome back for new tutors and coming back tutors. Thanks for agreeing to take tutes and lab classes for COMP1521 in 18s2. From last Semester experience I would like to make the following comments and please feel free to add to it. 1- The class is extremely big and we have to deal with lots of labs and submissions. Every lab has one tutor and one assistance. During the lab, I found that the best option is that the tutor helps students while the assistant marks the previous lab and put it in the sms. When you mark a student, please check if his/her all previous labs submitted and marked. 2- If you are unable to attend your lab for whatever reason, PLEASE write in here, I will do my best to cover you or have someone to do so. However, If you could find someone to replace you, that would be great too. In any replacement case you will need to fill THIS FORM and please you don'y have to email Mei Cheng. 3- We will talk about the assignment submission and marking whenever its due. 4- The most complaints I received last semester is about marks. Some people have their marks visible and some did not get it. We should of try to have all labs going together. I know it is not easy especially with the large number we are having this semester. Please, just do you best. Good Luck all, Have fun :) Wael ","answers":[]}]}